Guide to the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection of Oversized Material PE.040
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection of Oversized Material
1889-2014
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library
Bernstein, Rachel Amelia, 1953-
PE.040
4.75 Linear Feet in 4 oversize boxes and 2 flat-file drawers
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection of Oversized Material is an artificial collection, collected and assembled by the Tamiment Library over the course of several decades. It includes material related to other Printed Ephemera Collections at the Tamiment Library. Most of the material corresponds to organizations in PE 036, trade unions in PE 001, or individuals in PE 030.
Arrangement
Items are arranged alphabetically within folders.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Custodial History
The provenance of the materials is varied. Items were obtained through purchases, donations, standing orders with publishers, arrangements with labor unions and other organizations, exchanges with other libraries, and through ongoing collecting by Tamiment staff.
Scope and Content Note
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection of Oversized Material consists of large-scale items, which relate to other Printed Ephemera Collections at the Tamiment Library. These items were separated from collections and housed in appropriate containers because of their size. There are fliers, leaflets, broadsides, pamphlets and other publications in the collection. Items correspond to organizations such as the American Labor Party, the Black Panther Party, the Labour Party of Great Britain, the Workers Defense Union and the Committee for Maritime Unity. There are also items published by unions, for instance, materials relating to the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, the United Federation of Teachers, and the International Brotherhood of Teamsters. The material ranges in date from the late 1880s to 2014.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials in this collection have been compiled by the Tamiment Library.
Some materials were donated by Rachel Bernstein. The accession number associated with this material is 2014.172.
Bernstein, Rachel Amelia, 1953-
- 1199: Strike, 1959 (40 years later) (brochure), 1999 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- A. Seehof and Co. Verlag (Berlin, Germany), undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- All-Russian Council of Peasant Disputes (leaflet), 1917 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America (article), 1948 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America: Sydney Hillman (publication), 1948 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Amalgamated Lithographers of America: Local 1 (New York, NY) (publication), undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Amalgamated Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen of North America: Local 1 (publication), 1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Wokers Union (ACTWU) (placard), undated (Flat-file-folder 5 Right)
- America First Committee (broadside), undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
- American Civil Liberties Union 75th Anniversary Calendar, 1995 (Box Shared Tamiment MSOS006)
- American Committee on Africa (flier), 1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- American Federation of Labor - Congress of Industrial Organizations (7 items) (placards), 1960-1983; undated (Box Shared Tamiment MSXOS002, Folder 2)
- American Federation of Teachers (educational packet), undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- American Labor Party (3 items) (fliers), 1949, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- American Labor Party (broadside), undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
- American Labor Party (Railroad Workers Link special issue New York City Elections), 1949 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- American Labor Party: New York State (issue of Political Action newsletter), 1955 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- American League Against War and Fascism (flier), undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- American Lumberman (reprint), 1910 (Flat-file-folder 5 Right)
- American Peace Mobilization (2 items) (leaflets), 1941 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Americas Future, Inc. (leaflet), undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Anarchist Group of America and Canada: "Who Are the Real Enemies of the Working Class?" (leaflet), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Anti-Imperialist Activists (pamphlet), 1980 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Basta Ya! (booklet), undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Black Panthers: Committee to Defend the Panthers, Committee to Defend the Panther 21 (publication), circa 1970s (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Black Workers Organizing Committee (publication), undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Bridges-Robertson-Schmidt Defense Committee (leaflet), circa 1936 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Bridges-Robertson-Schmidt Defense Committee (leaflet), undated (Flat-file-folder 5 Right)
- Brookwood School (article), 1924 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- China Campaign Committee (flier), undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Citizens' Committee for the Election of Elizabeth Gurley Flynn to Congress (Bronx, NY) (circular letter), undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Civil Rights Congress (2 items) (leaflets), undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Civil Rights Congress (Pittsburgh Freedom News edition), undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Coalition of Labor Union Women (placard), 1975 (Flat-file-folder 5 Right)
- El Comite pro Huelga de Nueva York (poster in Spanish), circa 1934-1939 (Box Shared Tamiment MSOS006)
- Committee for Maritime Unity (flier), 1946 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Committee for Maritime Unity (Maritime Unity Bulletin, 2 items), 1946 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Committee for Maritime Unity (leaflet), undated (Flat-file-folder 5 Right)
- Committee of Martime Unions (broadside), undated (Flat-file-folder 5 Right)
- Committee on Militarism in Education (leaflet), 1937 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Commonwealth College (3 items) (leaflets), 1923, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Communist Party of Australia (publication), undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Communist Party of Great Britain (leaflet), undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Compressed Air and Free Air, Shaft, Tunnel, Foundation, Caisson, Subway, Cofferdam, Sewer Construction Workers of New York & New Jersey States & Vicinity, Local 147 (Sandhogs) (placard), undated (Flat-file-folder 5 Right)
- Congress of Racial Equality (placard), undated (Box Shared Tamiment MSXOS002, Folder 3)
- Co-operative Commonwealth Federation (Canada) (2 items) (fliers), undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Co-operative Commonwealth Federation (Canada) (leaflet), undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Daily News Strike (placards), 1990 (Box Shared Tamiment MSXOS002, Folder 4)
- Debs Freedom Conference (leaflet), undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Defense Committee for the Prisoners of Texas (leaflet), undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Fabian Society (leaflet), 1920 (Flat-file 6, Drawer 14, Folder A-M)
- Farmers' Educational Fund (Denver, CO) (Unity Builds Democracy! Don't Plow it Under! pamphlet), undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Feuilleton (publication), 1914 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Friends of Malatesta (publication), undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Gompers, Samuel (2 items) (Samuel Gompers-Labor Memorial, souvenir brochures), 1933 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Industrial Workers of the World (2 items) (leaflets), undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Industrial Workers of the World (2 items) (leaflets), undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Industrial Workers of the World: Informational calendars, 1972-1974 (Box Shared Tamiment 016, Folder 8-10)
- Institute for American Democracy (poster), undated (Flat-file 6, Drawer 14)
- International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen and Helpers of America: Warehouse and Distribution Workers, Local 688 (commemorative publication), 1951 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- International Committee of the Fourth International (London) (leaflet), 1976 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- International Labor Defense (2 items) (fliers), 1938 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union ("The Big Shot" ILGWU Super-Kid Convention Issue), 1944 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (Daily News newspaper clipping), 1939 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (Pins and Needles publication), 1938 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union ("The Triangle Fire" article), undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
- International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (Union Label advertisement), circa 1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union: Local 89 (New York, NY) (leaflet), undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Jewish Daily Forward (anniversary program), undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Labor Committee for Peaceful Alternatives (flier), circa 1955 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Labor League for Thomas and Nelson (leaflet), undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Labour Party of Great Britain (13 items), 1937-1950, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Labour Party of Great Britain (7 items), 1937-1950, undated (Flat-file-folder 9 Right, Drawer 14)
- "The Laurelled Chefs D'oeuvre D'art" (Paris Exhibition) (pamphlet), 1889 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- League for Industrial Democracy (brochure), circa 1937 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Liberal Party (brochure), undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Liberal Party: Goldstein, Jonah J. For a Better Living in a Greater City (comic book), undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Matteotti League (flier), undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Medical Bureau and North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy (2 items) (fliers), undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- National Assembly of Democratic Rights (broadside), undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- National Child Labor Committee (leaflet), 1928 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- National Civil Liberties Bureau (2 items) (fliers), undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- National Committee Unemployed Councils of U.S. (leaflet), undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
- National Council for the Prevention of War (flier), undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- National Council for the Prevention of War (leaflet), 1931 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- National Council of Labour (flier), undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- National Council for Universal and Unconditional Amnesty (leaflet), circa 1976 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- National Federation for Constitutional Liberties (leaflet), undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- National Federation for Constitutional Liberties (flier), undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- National Federation of Telephone Workers (The Telephone Worker), 1947 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- National Lawyers Guild (leaflet), undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
- National Negro Congress (broadside), undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- National Student League (flier), undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Newspaper clippings, publications, prints: Labor, Mother Jones; The Coming Nation; der Triumph der Arbeit, 1892-1933 (Box Shared Tamiment 010, Folder 1, 17)
- New Haven Committee to Defend the Panthers (leaflet), undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
- New Haven Panther Defense Committee (leaflet), circa 1970 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- New Haven Panther Defense Committee (leaflet) I, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
- New Haven Panther Defense Committee (leaflet) II, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
- New Mobilization Committee (brochure), 1969 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- New York Call (2 items) (commemorative checks), 1916 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- New York Call (leaflet), undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- New York Call (publication), 1918 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- New York Council for a Permanent FEPC (flier), undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- New York Council for a Permanent FEPC (leaflet), 1946 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- New York Election Ballots: Assembly Districts of New York (5 items), 1895-1914 (Box 2, Folder 9, Box Shared Tamiment 152, Folder 6)
- New York Election Ballots: Borough of the Bronx: Calendar (1 item), 1911 (Box 2, Folder 9, Flat-file-folder 1 Left, Box Shared Tamiment 152, Folder 6)
- New York Election Ballots: County of Kings (2 items), 1908-1913 (Box 2, Folder 9, Flat-file-folder 1 Left, Box Shared Tamiment 152, Folder 6)
- New York Election Ballots: County of Queens (2 items), 1903-1904 (Box 2, Folder 9, Flat-file-folder 1 Left, Box Shared Tamiment 152, Folder 6)
- New York Election Ballots (no district), 1908-1932 (Box 2, Folder 9, Flat-file-folder 1 Left, Box Shared Tamiment 152)
- New York Labor Conference for Peace (leaflet), undated (Flat-file-folder 1 Left)
- New York SANE (Committee for a SANE Nuclear Policy) (placard), 1961 (Flat-file-folder 9 Left)
- November 4th Coalition (leaflet), undated (Flat-file-folder 1 Left)
- Oltrecortina (flier), undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Panther Defense Committee (flier), circa 1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Parti Communiste Internationaliste (flier), undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Parti Communiste Internationaliste (leaflet), undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Progressive Mine Workers of America: Women's Auxilary (leaflet), 1933 (Box Shared Tamiment 152, Folder 6)
- Progessive Party (leaflet), circa 1952 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Proletarian Unity League (booklet), 1975 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Railway Labor Executives' Association (broadside), undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Reichstag Fire Trial Anniversary Committee (advertisement), 1943 (Box Shared Tamiment 152)
- Remember the Triangle Fire (posters), 2011-2016 (Flat-file-folder 1 Left)
- Resist (leaflet), undated (Box Shared Tamiment 152, Folder 6)
- Revolutionary Student Brigade (leaflet), circa 1976 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Revolutionary Student Brigade (booklet), undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Revolutionary Student Brigade (booklet), undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Revolutionary Student Brigade (pamphlet), undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Revolutionary Student Brigade/ Communist Youth Organization (leaflet), undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Revolutionary Union (leaflet), 1974 (Flat-file-folder 1 Left)
- Sandanista National Liberation Front (banner), undated (Flat-file-folder 10)
- Scottish Socialist Summer School (leaflet), 1908 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Screen Actors Guild - American Federation of Television and Radio Artists (SAG-AFTRA) (placard), undated (Flat-file-folder 9 Left)
- Seeger, Pete (album jacket), undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Self Defense Committee of the 17 Smith Act Victims (broadside), undated (Box Shared Tamiment 152, Folder 6)
- Social Service Employees Union, Local 371 (calendar), 1985 (Box Shared Tamiment 152, Folder 6)
- Socialist Labour League (leaflet), undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Socialist Labour League (booklet), 1969 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Socialist Labour League (pamphlet), circa 1965 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Socialist Labor League (booklet), 1970 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Socialist Labour League (pamphlet) I, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Socialist Labour League (pamphlet) II, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Socialist Party (U.S.) (leaflet), undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Solidarity Day (24 items) (placards), Sept 19 1981 (Box Shared Tamiment MSXOS002, Folder 1, Flat-file-folder 10)
- Solidarity London (brochure), undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Southern Summer School for Workers (2 items) (fliers), 1939-1941 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Springhill Mine Disaster: (The Springhill Record, publication), 1959 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Syracuse Peace Council Bookstore (broadside), undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Tamiment Library for the Graduate Student Orgnaizing Committee (GSOC) (placard), early 2000s (Flat-file-folder 9 Left)
- Tribune (5 items) (pamphlets), undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
- United Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America (UAW) (publication), 1989 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- United Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America (UAW), District 65 (placard), undated (Flat-file-folder 9 Left)
- United Federation of Teachers (publication), 1966 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- United Federation of Teachers (The United Teacher, photocopies), 1963 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- United May Day Committee (leaflet), circa 1976 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- U.S.-China Frienship Association (flier), circa 1971 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Vietnam Solidarity Committee (flier), undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Vietnam Veterans Against the War (3 items) (leaflets), undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Woman's Trade Union League (leaflet), undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Workers' Committee Against Wage Controls (pamphlet), 1973 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Workers Defense Union (4 items) (leaflets), circa 1919 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- World War Objectors (New York, NY) (leaflet), undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Young Lords Organization (leaflet), undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Young Workers' Liberation League (4 items) (assorted leaflets), 1970 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Young Worker on May Day (flier), undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Zapata, Emiliano (publication), 1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)